Guide to the New York State College of Human Ecology honors theses, 1970-2017.
New York State College of Human Ecology honors theses, 1970-2018.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York State College of Human Ecology honors theses, 1970-2017.
23-11-3264.
New York State College of Human Ecology.
8 cubic ft.
Theses.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.
Honors theses from the College of Human Ecology classes of 1970-2017.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Honors theses from the classes of 1970-2012 include compilers Jon White, Tamara Lynn Clark, Stephen Rulyak, Tara White, Cheryl L. Meehan, Kristine Marchalonis, Courtney Abrams, Mai Longden, Atish Shah, Cara Harth, Neil Shouba, Brett Oberst, Anika Trancik, Jennefer Allyn Russo, Robert Cohen, Gregory Bassuk, Jennifer Gorrelick, Amy Carpenter, Beth Ann Clauss, Tammy Freeberg, Jeannine Morrone, Margaret Kyle, Leslie Moskowitz, Carrie Ortiz, Robyn Altman, Michael Buff, Gaby Maimon, David Jackrel, David Rodin, Mary Beth Turell, Deirdre Cohen, Michael Siegel, Tina Shiau, Elizabeth Bowdish, Aaron David Tax, Amy Schreier, Hoi-Yan Erica Chan, Claire Ryan, Susan Metosky, Albert Ting, Matthew Semino, Rebecca Pinchoff, Sandra Irlen, Elyse Kantrowitz, Arjun Joshi, Jennifer Amengual, Nathaniel J. Dorfman, Rema Hanna, Sara E. Best, May L. Tan, Leslie Alkalay, Alison Moed, Julie Pranikoff, Ilene West, Matthew Mandel, Roberta Lynn Paikoff, Adrienne Bello, Patrick Collins, Joan E. Manhardt, Marc Rachman, Bruce Stephen Stuart, Stephen Wright, Katharina Boser, Lauren Kidder McGarry, Wendy Schuman, Maj-Stina Lunstrum, Mariano Macqueda, David Tate, Sarah Seidman, Seth Axelrod, Bonnie McIntosh, Amy Sussman, Ann Marie White, Nicole Allen, Michael Brezsnyak, Natalie Sikka, Allison Halpern, Kerri Aaron, Arielle S. Berman, Karin Price, Denisse Jovel Van Vonderen, David Biek, David A. Sbarra, Sudwiti Chanda, Sharon Flicker, Nancy Raitano, Nisha Antony, Courtney Rennicke, Caitlin Dunning, Meghan Gillan, Todd Jusko, Annie Roth, Donna Santoro, Jennifer Zanko, Meghan Butryn, Sarah Ka-Wah Yeung, Heather Lord, Courtney Berry, Krista Beiswenger, Jessica Benas, Jessica Conser, Varrie Davies, David Lee, Erica Levin, Erica Liberman, Thomas Olino, Annie Rosenburg, Vaeraanong Stakhao, Suzanne Saufer, Elena Ershova, Llana Kramer, Sarah Bufferd, Katy Devine, Randi Dublin, Michelle Finnegan, Allison Friedman, Yoko Iwaki, Tara Kakaty, Caryn Kerman, Robert Latzman, Jospeh Marasia, Sara Rosenblum, Dana Shanis, Kiran Sunkavalli, Harris Tescher, Corissa Lynn Callahan, Kathryn Howell, Jason Kwartner, Victoria Liang, Stacey Jennifer Lipitz, Noah M. Meyers, Kimberly Ann Notheis, Jessica Richards, Lindsay B. Slater, Maryann Totino, Rachel Theresa Ziwich, Nicole S. Simon, Hanna Muenke, Jennifer L. Rosenblum, Mark Celano, Judith Katz, Elizabeth Riccardi, Brittany Cohen, Abbie Dinowitz, Margaret Gichane, Keren Lerner, Martha Dee Kayser, Matthew Robert Nulty and Allison Nicole Lipitz.
Compilers from 2013 include Julie Avrutine, Marie Camerota, Shelby Distenfeld, Maggie Diu, Natalie Finn, Meera Menon, Rebecca A. Morgan, Zachary Nollet, Brittany Tusa and Anu Lingala.
Compilers from 2014 include Victoria Atzl, Martina Azar, Elizabeth DuPre, Evelyn Fok, Lara Gentilini, Samantha Marfurt and Meghan McDarby.
Compilers from 2015 include Yeo Jin Ahn, Chelsea Brite, Katelyn Fletcher, Zoe Amelia Katz, Devin Massaro, Brian Meagher, and Grace Monks.
Compilers from 2016 include James Dunlea, Francis Trenel, Misha Inniss-Thompson, Azraa Janmohamed, Aaron Wei-Feng Lee, Kathleen McCormick, Taylor McGuire and Paisley Terenzi.
Compilers from 2017 include Anna Claire Fernandez, Angel Khuu, Brian LaGrant, Leona Marie Sharpstene, Sharnendra Sidhu, Hsiang Ling Tsai, Deaven Winebrake and Sohyun Lee.
Compilers from 2018 include Matthew Avila, Gregory Chen, Stacey Chen, Xi Richard Chen, Tati Guzman, Alize Hill, Anita Jegarl, Jessica Kruse, Julia Lesnick, Daniel Rosenfeld, Emily Rosenthal, Laura Sheridan, Greta Ives Sloan and Alexandria Stansell.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Human Ecology.; Aaron, Kerri.; Abrams, Courtney.; Agarwal, Anshu.; Ahn, Yeo Jin.; Alkalay, Leslie.; Allen, Nicole; Altman, Robyn.; Amengual, Jennifer.; Anthony, Nisha.; Atzel, Victoria.; Aviila, Matthew.; Avrutine, Julie.; Axelrod, Seth.; Azar, Martina.; Bassuk, Gregory.; Beiswenger, Krista.; Bello, Adrienne.; Benas, Jessica.; Berman, Arielle S.; Bernardo, Katrina; Berry, Courtney; Best, Sara E.; Biek, David.; Biernbaum, Mark Aaron.; Boser, Katarina.; Bowdish, Elizabeth.; Brezsnyak, Michael.; Brite, Chelsea.; Buff, Michael.; Bufferd, Sarah.; Butryn, Meghan.; Callahan, Lynn Corissa.; Camerota, Marie.; Carpenter, Amy.; Celano, Mark.; Chan, Hoi-Yan Erica.; Chen, Gregory.; Chen, Stacey.; Chen, Xi Richard.; Clark, Tamara Lynn.; Clauss, Beth Ann.; Cohen, Brittany.; Cohen, Robert.; Cohen, Deirdre.; Collins, Patrick.; Conser, Jessica.; Davies, Carrie.; Devine, Katy.; Dinowitz, Abbie.; Distenfeld, Shelby.; Diu, Maggie.; Dorfman, Nathaniel J.; Driebe, Nicole M.; Dublin, Randi.; Dunning, Caitlin.; DuPre, Elizabeth.; Entin, Lena.; Ershova, Elena.; Finn, Natalie.; Finnegan, Allison.; Flicker, Sharon.; Evelyn, Fok.; Fletcher, Katelyn.; Freeberg, Tammy.; Friedman, Allison.; Fuligni, Andrew.; Gentilini, Lara.; Gichane, Margaret.; Gillan, Meghan.; Goldfarb, Dori Ellen.; Gorrelick, Jennifer.; Guzman, Tati.; Hanna, Rema.; Halpern, Allison.; Harth, Cara.; Highsmith, Jason.; Hill, Alize.; Howell, Kathryn; Irlen, Sandra.; Jackrel, David.; Jegarl, Anita.; Joshi, Arjun.; Jusko, Todd.; Kakaty, Tara.; Kantrowitz, Elyse.; Katz, Judith.; Katz, Zoe Amelia.; Kayser, Dee Martha.; Kerman, Caryn.; Kramer, Llana.; Kruse, Jessica.; Kwartner, Jason.; Kyle, Margaret.; LaVallee, Sarah.; Latzman, Robert.; Lee, David.; Lerner, Keren.; Lesnick, Julia.; Levin, Erica.; Levitt, Ariana.; Liang, Victoria.; Liberman, Erica.; Lipitz, Stacey Jennifer.; Lipitz, Allison Nicole.; Longden, Mai.; Lord, Heather.; Lunstrum, Stina-Maj.; Maimon, Gaby.; Mandel, Matthew.; Manhardt, Joan E.; Marasia, Joseph.; Marchalonis, Kristine.; Marfurt, Samantha.; Maqueda, Mariano.; Massaro, Devin.; McDarby, Meghan L.; McGarry, Lauren Kidder.; McIntosh, Bonnie.; Meagher, Brian.; Meehan, Cheryl L.; Metosky, Susan.; Meyers, Noah M.; Moed, Alison.; Monks, Grace.; Morgan, Rebecca.; Morrone, Jeannine.; Moskowitz, Leslie.; Muenke, Hanna.; Nollet, Zachary.; Notheis, Kimberly Ann.; Nulty, Matthew Robert.; Oberst, Brett.; Ojalehto, Bethany; Olino, Thomas.; Ortiz, Carrie.; Paikoff, Roberta Lynn.; Pauker, Stacey.; Pinchoff, Rebecca.; Poliskin, Dara; Pranikoff, Julie.; Price, Karin.; Purington, Amanda.; Rachman, Marc.; Raitano, Nancy.; Rennicke, Courtney.; Riccardi, Elizabeth.; Richards, Jessica.; Rodin, David.; Rosenbaum, Jennifer L.; Rosenblum, Sara.; Rosenburg, Annie.; Rosenfeld, Daniel.; Roth, Annie.; Rulyak, Stephen.; Russo, Jennefer Allyn.; Ryan, Claire.; Santoro, Donna.; Saufer, Suzanne.; Sbarra, David A.; Schreier, Amy.; Schuman, Wendy.; Seidman, Sarah.; Semino, Matthew.; Shah, Atish.; Shanis, Dana.; Sheridan, Laura.; Shiau, Tina.; Shouba, Neil.; Siegel, Alana.; Siegel, Michael.; Sikka, Natalie.; Simon, Nicole S.; Slater, Lindsay B.; Sloan, Greta Ives.; Smith, Shannon L.; Stansell, Alexandria.; Stuart, Bruce Stephen.; Sudwiti, Chanda.; Sunkavalli, Kiran.; Sussman, Amy.; Tan, May Lynn.; Tate, David.; Tax, Aaron David.; Tesher, Harris.; Ting, Albert.; Totino, Maryann.; Trancik, Anika.; Turell, Mary Beth.; Tusa, Brittany.; Van Vonderen, Denisse Jovel.; Veraanong, Srakhao.; Wechsler, Rachel.; West, Ilene.; White, Ann Marie.; White, Jon.; White, Tara.; Wong, Nina.; Wright, Stephen.; Yeung, Sarah Ka-Wah.; Yoko, Iwaki.; Zanko, Jennifer.; Ziwich, Rachel Theresa.; Dunlea, James Patrick.; Francis, Terenel E.; Inniss-Thompson, Misha.; Janmohamed, Azraa.; Lee, Aaron Wei-Feng.; McCormick, Kathleen.; McGuire, Taylor.; Terenzi, Paisley.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University. Class of 1986 and Before.; Cornell University. Class of 1987.; Cornell University. Class of 1988.; Cornell University. Class of 1989.; Cornell University. Class of 1990.; Cornell University. Class of 1991.; Cornell University. Class of 1992.; Cornell University. Class of 1993.; Cornell University. Class of 1994.; Cornell University. Class of 1995.; Cornell University. Class of 1996.; Cornell University. Class of 1997.; Cornell University. Class of 1998.; Cornell University. Class of 1999.; Cornell University. Class of 2000.; Cornell University. Class of 2001.; Cornell University. Class of 2002.; Cornell University. Class of 2003.; Cornell University. Class of 2004.; Cornell University. Class of 2005.; Cornell University. Class of 2006.; Cornell University. Class of 2007.; Cornell University. Class of 2008.; Cornell University. Class of 2012.; Cornell University. Class of 2013.; Cornell University. Class of 2014.; Cornell University. Class of 2015.; Cornell University. Class of 2016.; Cornell University. Class of 2017.; Cornell University. Class of 2018.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Some of the theses are available online by clicking here.
For additional theses see the Division of Nutritional Sciences Honors Theses collection, #29-06-3419
Submission Release Forms are in Box 9.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Classes of 1970-1975; 1982; 1986
Series II. Class of 1987
Series III. Class of 1988
Series IV. Class of 1989
Series V. Class of 1990
Series VI. Class of 1991
Series VII. Class of 1992
Series VIII. Class of 1993
Series IX. Class of 1994
Series X. Class of 1995
Series XI. Class of 1996
Series XII. Class of 1997
Series XIII. Class of 1998
Series XIV. Class of 1999
Series XV. Class of 2000
Series XVI. Class of 2001
Series XVII. Class of 2002
Series XVIII. Class of 2003
Series XIX. Class of 2004
Series XX. Class of 2005
Series XXI. Class of 2006
Series XXII. Class of 2007
Series XXIII. Class of 2008
Series XXIV. Class of 2012
Series XXV. Class of 2013
Series XXVI. Class of 2014
Series XXVII. Class of 2015
Series XXVIII. Class of 2016
Series XXIX. Class of 2017
Series XXX. Class of 2018
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Classes of 1970-1975; 1982; 1986
  - "A Comparative Analysis of the Inherent Characteristics and Physical Properties of Garment Leather with Implications for the Design and Construction of Apparel", 1970; Corcoran, Phyllis (Box 9)
  - "A Study of Dress Worn by American Women in the 1920s", 1970; Heydinger, Beth Ann (Box 9)
  - "Fashion and Consumer Welfare", 1970; Postle, Susan Louise (Box 9)
  - "Relations Between Thermal Shrinkage and Draw Ratios of Nylon 66", 1970; Sinclair, Nancy Jo (Box 9)
  - "A Comprehensive Study of the Use of Non-flammable Fabrics for Children's Sleepware", 1971; Johnson, Natalie (Box 9)
  - "A Study of Felting Properties of Wool", 1971; Norton, Marjorie (Box 9)
  - "Flammable Fabrics: The Retailer's Plight", 1972; Berry, Carolyn (Box 9)
  - "A Laboratory and Wear Study of the Appearance and Performance of Boy's Durable Press Pants", 1972; Douglas, Ruby Jean (Box 9)
  - "The Restoration and Classification of Certain Items from the Cornell Costume Collection", 1972; Halleran, Kristine (Box 9)
  - "The Development of Consumer Interest in the Home Sewing of Lingerie", 1972; Sielschott, Jeri Lynn (Box 9)
  - "Thermal Insulative Qualities of Various Fabric Systems as Related to Skiwear", 1972; Kayser, Martha Dee (Box 10)
  - "Effect of Fast Electrons on Polyethylene Terephthalate", 1973; Wieder, Ann Louise (Box 9)
  - "The Restoration of Degraded Cotton by Interfacial Polymerization with Nylon 66", 1974; David, Laurie F. (Box 9)
  - "Flame Retardant Clothing for the Elderly - A Feasability Report", 1974; Fisher, Charlene (Box 9)
  - "Evaluation of the Wear Life of Men's Trouser Pockets", 1974; Graceffo, Elaine (Box 9)
  - "The Patchwork Quilt in America: A Chronicle of Authentic Americana", 1975; Schreier, Maura (Box 9)
  - "Dominance Behavior in a Group of Adolescent Females", 1982; Paikoff, Roberta Lynn (Box 9)
  - "Effects of Rapid Television Segment Pacing on Attention and Content Comprehension of Preschool Children", 1986; Bello, Adrienne (Box 6)
  - "The Roles of Mentoring and Tacit Knowledge in the Career Development of Business Managers", 1986; Collins, Patrick (Box 6)
  - "Relation Between Maternal Behavior and Children's Peer-Directed Helping Behavior", 1986; Manhardt, Joan E. (Box 6)
  - "The Young Child's Eyewitness Abilities: Can Preschool Children Invalidate Their Testimony Through Protectively Withholding Information?", 1986; Rachman, Marc (Box 6)
  - "The Relationship Between Self-Esteem and a Desire to Change One's Physical Appearance During Either Adolescence or Adulthood", 1986; Stuart, Bruce Stephen (Box 6)
- Series II. Class of 1987
- Series III. Class of 1988
  - "Adolescent Teasing and Ridicule and Their Relationships With Self-esteem and Social Personality", 1988; Fuligni, Andrew J. (Box 3)
  - "Children's Word Learning: A Study of Effects of Linguistic Contrast and Conceptual Hierarchy", 1988; Goldfarb, Dori Ellen (Box 3)
  - "A Taxonomy and Ecology of Non-contact significant Others", 1988; Wright, Stephen (Box 6)
- Series IV. Class of 1989
  - "The First Language Acquisition of German Word Order: A Study of Verb Order and Verb Related Constituent Order", 1989; Boser, Katharina (Box 6)
  - "Religiosity and Marital Satisfaction: Intergenerational and Intragenerational Influences", 1989; McGarry, Laurne Kidder (Box 6)
- Series V. Class of 1990
  - "Discrepancies Between Internal Gender Identity and External Gender Expression, in a College-Aged Sample of Homosexual Men, and Their Relation to Psychological Adjustment", 1990; Biernbaum, Mark Aaron (Box 3)
  - "The Cognitive Interview modified and applied with young children", 1990; Schuman, Wendy (Box 6)
- Series VI. Class of 1991
  - "Eating Disorders in a Normal College Population", 1991; Lunstrum, Maj-Stina (Box 6)
  - "Examining the Existence of a Confirmation Bias in Hypothesis Testing Situations", 1991; Maqueda, Mariano (Box 6)
  - "Academic Grades: What Do They Mean and How Do They Relate to Motivational Factors?", 1991; Tate, David (Box 6)
  - "Sorority Rush Participants", 1991; Seidman, Sarah (Box 6)
- Series VII. Class of 1992
  - "A Case Study of Student Empowerment as Sustained by the Community Learning and Service Partnership Program", 1992; White, Jon (Box 1)
  - "Involvement in Popular American Culture, Body Image Distortion, and Eating Disordered Characteristics", 1992; Axelrod, Seth (Box 6)
  - "Friendships During the First Year of College: Predicting Satisfaction and Closeness", 1992; McIntosh, Bonnie (Box 6)
  - "Distinguishing Between Children's Real and Imagined Stories: Adults' Accuracy and the Characteristics to Which they Attend", 1992; Sussman, Amy (Box 6)
  - "Social, Family, and Maternal Predictors of School-Readiness in 6 Year Old Caucasian Children", 1992; White, Ann Marie (Box 6)
- Series VIII. Class of 1993
  - "The Cognitive Effects of Low-Level Lead Exposure on Serial Reversal Learning", 1993; Clark, Tamara Lynn (Box 1)
  - "The Relationships Between Cholesterol, Sleep and Depression", 1993; Rulyak, Stephen (Box 1)
  - "Children's Testimony and Suggestibility", 1993; White, Tara (Box 1)
  - "Bulimia and Chronic Dieting Among College Students: The Role of Family Functioning, Depression and Achievement Motivation", 1993; Allen, Nicole (Box 6)
- Series IX. Class of 1994
  - "The Development of the Eating Traits Inventory", 1994; Meehan, Cheryl Lynne (Box 1)
  - "Neuropsychological Effects of Low-Level Lead Exposure in Toddlers", 1994; Marchalonis, Kristine (Box 1)
  - "Multiple Stressors: Single Parenting and Residential Density Among African-Americans", 1994; Abrams, Courtney (Box 1)
  - "The Effect of Health Care Reform on the Elderly in Rural Communities", 1994; Longden, Mai (Box 1)
  - "The Pain-Reducing and Calming Effects of Lactose Protein and Fat (Milk Components) on Human Newborns", 1994; Shah, Atish (Box 1)
  - "Roles of Dietary Carbohydrate, Protein, and Kilocalories in Ingestion Responsiveness and Survivorship in Drosophila Melanogaster, 1994; Harth, Cara (Box 1)
  - "An Analysis of the Disease Concept of Alcoholism", 1994; Shouba, Neil (Box 1)
  - "An Analysis of the Growth and Development of Alternative Dispute Resolution Programs in the U.S.", 1994; Oberst, Brett (Box 1)
  - "Future Places for Children: A Discussion about Facilities", 1994; Trancik, Anika (Box 1)
  - "A Comparative Case Study of Three Peer Sexuality Education Programs in the US and Great Britain: What Can We Learn From Each Other?", 1994; Russo, Jennefer Allyn (Box 1)
  - "An Economic Model of State Government Making"], 1994; Cohen, Robert (Box 1)
  - "United States National Service Policy 1989-1992", 1994; Bassuk, Gregory (Box 1)
  - "Restaurant Accessibility: Compliance with the Americans with Disabilities Act, Title III", 1994; Gorrelick, Jennifer (Box 1)
  - "An Analysis of the Legal Rights of Women with Mild Mental Retardation to Retain Custody of Their Children", 1994; Carpenter, Amy (Box 1)
  - "Parent Involvement in Head Start Programs", 1994; Driebe, Nicole M. (Box 3)
  - "Reliability and Stability of Visual Expectation and Reaction Time from Two to Three Months", 1994; Brezsnyak, Michael (Box 6)
  - "Parent Involvement in Head Start Programs", 1994; Driebe, Nicole (Box 3)
  - "Information Processing in Lead-Exposed Toddlers", 1994; Sikka, Natalie (Box 6)
- Series X. Class of 1995
  - "Head Start Teachers' Attitudes on Parental Involvement", 1995; Clauss, Beth Ann (Box 1)
  - "The Impact of NYS Health Dept. Regulations on a Boy Scout Council's Summer Camp Program", 1995; Freeberg, Tammy (Box 1)
  - "Personality and Preferred Wake-Up Time and Preferred Bedtime in Female College Students", 1995; Morrone, Jeannine (Box 1)
  - "The Role of Reputation in Product Quality: An Examination of the Generic Drug Industry", 1995; Kyle, Margaret (Box 1)
  - "The College of Human Ecology: A Liberalizing Force in the Attitudes of First Year Students?", 1995; Highsmith, Jason M. (Box 3)
  - "Socializing Their Own: Home Economists, Summer Work, and Cornell University", 1995; Halpern, Allison (Box 3)
  - "Growth Curves for Speed of Information Processing in Infants", 1995; Aaron, Kerri (Box 6)
  - "Self-Disclosure: Personal Style or Situation Effect?", 1995; Berman, Arielle S. (Box 6)
  - "Diffenential Substantiation of Child Sexual Abuse Allegations: Age-and Gender-Related Trends", 1995; Price, Karin (Box 7)
- Series XI. Class of 1996
  - "The Design of Playgrounds", 1996; Moskowitz, Leslie (Box 1)
  - "Preschool Playground Observation Project", 1996; Ortiz, Carrie (Box 1)
  - "Parenting Issues in an Urban Setting: The Support Systems, Strengths, and Needs of the Beginning With Children School Parents", 1996; Van Vonderen, Denisse Jovel (Box 3)
  - "Perceived and Enacted Social Support", 1996; Biek, David (Box 7)
  - "Uncommitted Sexual Behavior Among College Students", 1996; Sbarra, David A. (Box 7)
  - "An Investigation into the Impact of Foster Care Subsidies on the Quantity of Foster Care Services Supplied", 1996; Doyle, Joseph (Box 9)
  - "Supply Responses to Foster Care Subsidy Rates: An Empirical Investigation", 1996; Doyle, Joseph (Box 9)
  - "An Analyses of Characteristics Affecting the Length of Time Until Termination of Parental Rights in New York State Adoption Cases", 1996; Jacobs, Brian Adam (Box 9)
- Series XII. Class of 1997
  - "Family Interaction Patterns Related to Fruits and Vegetables", 1997; Altman, Robyn (Box 1)
  - "Labeled Phi-X-174 Bacteriophage as a Test of Surgical Gown Barrier Effectiveness", 1997; Buff, Michael (Box 1)
  - "Mechanisms Underlying the Development of the Corticopontine Tract in the Golden Hamster", 1997; Maimon, Gaby (Box 1)
  - "Molecular Orientation of Spider Silk Upon Supercontraction and Extension", 1997; Jackrel, David (Box 1)
  - "An Examination of Extracted and Unextracted Urinary Cortisol Levels as Indicators of Stress in Humans", 1997; Rodin, David (Box 1)
  - "Designing Apparel for the Mature Woman", 1997; Turell, Mary Beth (Box 1)
  - "Ovine Placentomal Eversion: An Examination of its Functional Significance and Controlling Mechanism", 1997; Cohen, Deirdre (Box 1)
  - "The Effects of Nutrition Regulation Upon the Purchase and Consumption of Frozen Entrees", 1997; Siegel, Michael (Box 1)
  - "The Relationship Between Childhood Sexual Abuse and Somatization Disorder: A Study of College Women", 1997; Chanda, Sudwiti (Box 7)
  - "Family Development in Families that Adopt Older Children", 1997; Flicker, Sharon (Box 7)
  - "Stability and Predictive Validity of Infant Visual Information Processing from Infancy to Childhood", 1997; Raitano, Nancy (Box 7)
  - "The Relationship Between Child Sexual Abuse and Social Anxiety in Women", 1997; Antony, Nisha (Box 9)
- Series XIII. Class of 1998
  - "A Reestimation of the Returns to Attending an Elite Institution", 1998; Shiau, Tina (Box 1)
  - "Conceptualizations of Seasonal and Local Foods", 1998; Bowdish, Elizabeth (Box 1)
  - "Motivations for Volunteerism in Areas Pertaining to Child Welfare", 1998; Tax, Aaron David (Box 1)
  - "Physiological Stress in Response to 'Modern' and 'Species-old' Stressors in Children Living in Rural New York", 1998; Schreier, Amy (Box 1)
  - "Evaluation of a Residential Environment Assessment Scale", 1998; Chan, Hoi-Yan Erica (Box 1)
  - "Usability of a Regional Food Guide Among WIC Participants", 1998; Ryan, Claire (Box 2)
  - "The Role of Parents and Schools in Providing HIV/AIDS Education to Children and Adolescents", 1998 (Box 2)
  - "Talking with Kids about Aids", 1998 (Box 2)
  - "Relation of Chronic Stressors to Blood Pressure Recovery in Children", 1998; Ting, Albert (Box 2)
  - "Urban Poverty Reconsidered: Framing a New Development Paradigm", 1998; Semino, Matthew (Box 2)
  - "Children Should Be Heard", 1998; Pinchoff, Rebecca (Box 2)
  - "Long Term Effectiveness of Irlen Lenses and Risk Factors Related to Discontinued Use", 1998; Irlen, Sandra (Box 2)
  - "Parent Study: A Look At Parental Beliefs About HIV/AIDS", "The Role of Parents and Schools in Providing HIV/AIDS Education to Children and Adolescents", "Talking with Kids about Aids", 1998; Metosky, Susan (Box 2)
  - "Child Care in the Wake of Welfare Reform", 1998; Entin, Lena (Box 10)
- Series XIV. Class of 1999
  - "Case Study in Design Leadership", 1999; Kantrowitz, Elyse (Box 2)
  - "A General Approach to Non-Invasive Imaging of Transgenes Using CIS-Linked Herpes Simplex Virus Thymidine Kinase", 1999; Joshi, Arjun (Box 2)
  - "Good News for Dieters: Imprecise Control of Food Intake", 1999; Amengual, Jennifer (Box 2)
  - "Da'Spot - clothing store in Ithaca," three teams of students, 1999 (Box 2)
  - "Parental Marital Status and Academic Achievement at Cornell University", 1999; Dorfman, Nathaniel John (Box 2)
  - "The Effect of Body Size on the Labor Market", 1999; Hanna, Rema (Box 2)
  - "A Study of the Eating Patterns, Menstrual Cycle, and Exercise Habits in Females", 1999; Best, Sara Elizabeth (Box 2)
  - "A Forecast of Malnutrition by Regional Experts", 1999; Tan, May Lynn (Box 2)
  - "The Effects of Lead Exposure on Reversal Learning and IQ in Toddlers", 1999; Burnette, Mandi L. (Box 5)
  - "Attitudes of Parents, Teachers, and Administrators on Nine Areas of Educational Policy", 1999; Duane, John Thomas (Box 5)
  - "The Circulation of Trauma on an Intensive Care Burn Unit", 1999; Rennicke, Courtney (Box 7)
  - "The Effects of Kinship Care on Child Well-Being", 1998; Pauker, Stacey (Box 10)
  - "Tracking and Peer Culture: Does Grouping Affect Adolescent Social Norms?", 1999; Smith, Shannon (Box 10)
- Series XV. Class of 2000
  - "Cognitive Impairments in Patients with Anorexia Nervosa: the Effects of Absolute Body Weight, Nutritional Deficiencies, and Preoccupation", 2000; Alkalay, Leslie (Box 2)
  - "Differential Affective Response to a Dopamine Agonist as a Function of Extraversion", 2000; Moed, Alison (Box 2)